Sri Sainee Thirumurugan

Email: srisainee2310@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 413 931 624

Portfolio: https://littlebravesri.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sri-sainee-

thirumurugan/

GitHub: https://github.com/littlebravesri

Career Objective

Master of Data Science graduate having well developed teamwork, communication and problem-solving skills broadened during academic and work experience. Possessing extensive knowledge in Python, R, SQL, PowerBI and Azure through experience and projects. Confident about actively engaging in a dynamic and challenging environment to develop personal growth while contributing to the organization's success.

Education

Master of Data Science – RMIT University Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering) – Anna University July 2019 – June 2021 August 2015- May 2019

September 2021

September 2021

June 2021 October 2020

Certifications

Microsoft Student Accelerator program 2021
KPMG Virtual Data Analytics internship
Microsoft Azure fundamentals
The Sparks Foundation

Work Experience

Data and Analytics Officer

Dementia Australia, Melbourne

August 2021 - September 2021

- Identified different tags and triggers used in the forms via Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics to report of tracking activities such as link clicks and PDF downloads.
- Explored different marketing tools like MailChimp, Eventbrite, Formstack, Google Analytics to collect data for the purpose of visualization.
- Used Zapier to integrate the marketing tools to Google Sheets and created zaps to automate the addition of new or updated data into Google Sheets.
- Imported the data from Google sheets into PowerBI and performed various visualization as per the requirement of the marketing team.
- Documented the data preprocessing steps and data transformation performed in PowerBI.
- Delivered the visualization with a story to the marketing team to understand the monthly performance of their marketing websites.

Skills: PowerBI, Python, Story-telling, Agile/Scrum, Zapier, Google Sheets.

Data Analyst April 2021- July 2021

Wings CyberSpace International, Geelong

- Performed web scrapping on eBay using BeautifulSoup, Scrappy, ParseHub and Octoparse.
- Automated the web scrapping program to scrape multiple depth levels within a page.
- Carried out Data Preprocessing to clean the data for visualization.
- Designed dashboards using PowerBI and Tableau with data extracted from eBay.

Skills: Python. PowerBI, Tableau. Scrappy, BeautifulSoup, ParseHub.

Data Scientist

November 2020 - January 2021

Know your terms, Melbourne

- Extracted text from web pages using Beautiful Soup and Scrapy.
- Mined text from PDF and docx files for displaying relevant terms and conditions for the users.
- Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment.

Skills: Python, Scrappy, BeautifulSoup, Agile/Scrum

Academic Experience

AI Powered Voice Assistance using Alexa

March 2021 - May 2021 RMIT Cyber Ready Cloud Innovation Centre – The Museum of London

- Developed custom skills for Alexa using Python in Alexa Development Console.
- Integrated Trello Board with Alexa to read and update a card.
- Deployed skills in Alexa skill store.
- Attended multiple AWS workshops on building customer centric solutions.

Skills: API calls, AWS, Python, Requirement Elicitation and Documentation

Modelling Recyclable Materials Collected and Recycled of Victoria

March 2021 - June 2021

Work Integrated Learning – Sustainability Victoria

- Responsible for data collection of kurbside recycle materials of each Victorian council.
- Performed Data Preprocessing to clean the data sets.
- Designed various Machine Learning models such as Linear Regressions, Exponential Smoothing, XGBoost etc. to forecast future values of recycled materials.
- Designed Time Series models like ARIMA, FBprophet to predict future values of recycled materials.
- Assisted in creating the dashboard in Python to visualize the results of the models using Plotly.
- Documented the results of the models to compare and decide the best fit model for the data set.

Skills: Python, Data Analysis, Data Pre-processing, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Time Series Analysis, Agile/Scrum

Crimes of Victoria Dashboard

May 2020 – June 2020

RMIT University

- Visualize crimes dataset in a dashboard showing the rate of crimes occurred during the years 2016-2019.
- Story telling of the crime rates of Victoria using Shiny and R interactive visualizations.
- Deployed dashboard in shinyapps.io: https://littlebrayesri.shinyapps.io/Crimes/? ga=2.186900512.902303536.1602752634-734726441.1602752634

Skills: R, Data Visualization, Shiny app

Additional Projects

Translating American Sign Language to Text and Speech

July 2021 - August 2021

Microsoft Student Accelerator Program 2021

- Developed and end-to-end AI solution using Microsoft Azure services.
- Trained Machine Learning model on ASL alphabets using Azure Cognitive Services and Machine Learning Studio.
- Created web app that accessed the web camera to predict and display the ASL alphabets.
- Used JavaScript's SpeechSynthesis library to convert the text to speech.
- Deployed the web app in Azure Power Apps.

Skills: Microsoft Azure, Flask, API calls, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Machine Learning

Django Restful API Example Web App

April 2020 – May 2020

DataDisca Pyt Ltd

- Utilized Diango Rest Framework to make API calls.
- Created routes to access model based and model less APIs.
- Created API calls to create, update, delete and print user and product information in SQLite database.

Skills: API calls, Django Rest Framework.